Bharti Patel

UX Designer with background in Visual & Advertising

CONTACT

- **(**510) 221-8063
- bhartip0703@gmail.com
- San Francisco, CA
- in linkedin.com/in/bharti7
- bhartiux.github.io

TOOLS

Adobe Creative Suite Sketch3 InVision Corel Draw 17 MS Office HTML CSS Oracle Webcenter

SKILLS

User research
User personas
Data synthesis
Rapid prototype
Information architecture
Usability testing
Wireframes
Service design
Visual design

EDUCATION

General Assembly

San Francisco, CA
User Experience Design
Immersive program crafted
by top practitioners in the field
-10 weeks Full time
Diploma in Commercial Arts

Diploma in Commercial Arts Nirmala Niketan, India

CERTIFICATION

Academy X - Web Design Santa Clara, CA Learn IT - Computer Graphics San Mateo, CA

PROFILE

I'm a UX designer with a passion for creativity. I believe that simplicity is the ultimate sophistication – that less is more. I have an extensive background in graphic design, web design, and advertising. I bring my experience, passion, and professionalism to any creative task.

EXPERIENCE

UX Designer - Incorta April 2016-May 2016

- 3-weeks worked with Incorta that provides same-day analytics for business user & allows businesses to use data more quickly.
- Worked on the catalog section that needed clear and engaging interface.
- Provided solution by creating more user friendly, welcoming layout.
- User & stakeholder interviews, surveys, contextual inquiry, competitive and comparative analysis, and usability testing drove the design of the prototype.

UX Designer - San Francisco Bicycle Coalition (SFBC) March 2016-April 2016 (as part of General Assembly)

- 2-weeks project to design an mobile app that allows SFBC members to communicate and share with each other.
- User interviews, survey, competitive & comparative analysis, user flow, site maps, concept model, and wireframes. Usability testing drove the design of the prototype.

UX Designer - Progress Hardware - Ecommerce website March 2016 (as part of General Assembly)

- 2-weeks project to design an ecommerce website that helps to find right tool for loyal customers who don't like to go to stores, through detailed reviews, update inventory & same day shipping option.
- Used stakeholder interviews, competitive and comparative analysis, card sorting, and usability testing to inform design of global navigation as well as search and check out flows.

Web Designer - Ross Stores Inc. Dublin, CA Oct 2013- Dec 2015

- Researched & redesigned intranet portal using Adobe Creative suite & Oracle Webcenter.
- Created meaningful and compelling designs to help users become more productive and frequently visit the portal.
- Worked on design to be simpler and user friendly from complex and abstract material.
- Collaborated extensively across department & with various stakeholders.

Designer - Terminix Corp, Santa Clara, CA Aug 2009- May 2013

- Worked closely on presentations & administrative office work for sales and marketing managers
- Involved in maintaining clear and consistent communications to all departments, regarding bad debt account, and how to reinstate them.
- Worked closely with branch managers and regional managers.

Bharti Patel

UX Designer with background in Visual & Advertising

CONTACT

- **(**510) 221-8063
- bhartip0703@gmail.com
- San Francisco, CA
- in linkedin.com/in/bharti7
- bhartiux.github.io

TOOLS

Adobe Creative Suite Sketch3 InVision Corel Draw 17 MS Office HTML CSS Oracle Webcenter

SKILLS

User research
User personas
Data synthesis
Rapid prototype
Information architecture
Usability testing
Wireframes
Service design
Visual design

EDUCATION

General Assembly

San Francisco, CA
User Experience Design
Immersive program crafted
by top practitioners in the field
-10 weeks Full time
Diploma in Commercial Arts
Nirmala Niketan, India

CERTIFICATION

Academy X - Web Design Santa Clara, CA Learn IT - Computer Graphics San Mateo, CA

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Projects:

Web Designer - Drishticon, Fremont, CA Dec 2014 - Mar 2015

- Worked with owner & developers to improve the UI & Visuals of their current website.
- Recreated the current logo & the banners using Adobe Illustrator & Photoshop.

Graphic/ Web Designer - Infinilytics Inc, Santa Clara, CA May 2013 - Jul 2013

- Designed marketing and promotional materials across email, mobile, web, print, and social media.
- Created branding materials logo creation and reconstruction.
- Assisted others with layout and design worked with marketing department to improve the final product.

Project Manager - United Way SML, San Rafael, CA April 2009 - May 2009

- Worked as a project manager for redesigning the website for United Way Sonoma Mendocino Lake.
- Responsible for total needs of the client including management of technical and creative resource to deliver complete corporate- quality branding and web solutions.

Web Designer - Ondemandtek, Fremont, CA Jan 2009 - Mar 2009

- Worked with various design tools including Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Illustrator, and Flash to implement web designs and functionality
- Created Logo using Adobe illustrator.

Office Assistant - Terminix Corp, Santa Clara, CA Apr 2003- May 2004

- Worked closely on presentations & administrative office work for sales and marketing managers
- Involved in maintaining clear and consistent communications to all departments, regarding bad debt account, and how to reinstate them.
- Worked closely with branch managers and regional managers.